Okay. So, all I've done from last time
is I've hidden the elapse timer. So,
it's right here.
I wrapped it in curly braces so I could
hide it so you could focus on just the
code that I'm writing for this one. So,
what I want to show you is I want to
show you how you could console.log hello
after 3 seconds. If you wanted to do
that, you would say set timeout and then
it needs a function. Um, you could
either write this function outside or
I'm just going to define mine directly
inside. And I'm gonna say console.log
log
hello world and then after that I need
to have it wait 3 seconds.
So if I save this and I come over to my
code, waited 1 2 3 seconds and there's
my hello world and then my timer keeps
on going.
Well, what if I wanted to wait 3 seconds
and in a data retrieval sense, maybe I
retrieve data and it takes 3 seconds.
Hopefully, it doesn't actually take that
long, but for the sake of imagination,
it takes 3 seconds. Then, once I have
that data, I need to do something with
that data, which takes an additional 5
seconds. Um, but I don't want to start
that that 5-second process until I
finish the first 3 seconds. So, how
would I do that? Well, I'm going to show
you the wrong way first, and then I'll
show you the right way. So, if I wanted
the wrong way, you might think, "Oh,
well, I'll just set another timeout."
After this first timeout finishes um in
3 seconds, then I'll just start another
timeout. And I'll say console.log
hello world. And I will do that one
after 5 seconds because code runs from
top to bottom. So, we're going to do
that one and then that one. So, when we
save this and we come over, we wait one,
two, three. There's hello world. Four.
Five. Uh-oh. There's the hello world. 3
+ 5 is 8. Why did it print after 5?
Well, the answer is because we moved it
to the background by using set timeout.
It actually wasn't waiting for the other
process to complete. So, it already set
that one up and then it set that one up
immediately after. Then 3 seconds went
by and printed hello world. And then the
remaining 2 seconds went by and it
printed hello world again. Well, that's
problematic. We didn't want to start the
5-second wait until we finish the 3-se
secondond wait. That would be like
trying to process the data that we don't
even have yet.
So to handle that, what we could do,
what we'll need to do is we'll need to
actually move this function
inside of this function. So if we want
to make this function multi-line, we
have to use curly braces. So there's the
curly braces and I'm going to format my
code real quick. Then I'm going to take
this set timeout and I'm going to move
it inside. Okay. So now it's going to
after 3 seconds it's going to say hello
world and then it's going to set a
timeout for another 5 seconds. So if we
save this and we come over 1 2 3 there's
our first hello world. 4 5 6 7 8 there's
our second hello world. And then our
code's just going to keep on ticking.
Um, but as you can see,
in order for that to happen, I had to
nest this inside of